Guide to the Keith-McHenry-Pond Family Papers, 1841-1961
The Bancroft Library.
- Grinnell, Joseph, 1877-1939 See California. University, Berkeley. Museum of Vertebrate Zoology
- Gump, Abraham Livingston, 1869-1947 See also: Gump (S. G.) Company, San Francisco
  - 4 letters, 1910, to William Keith.
  - Letter, Mar. 19, 1931, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Gump (S. G.) Company, San Francisco See also: Gump, Abraham Livingston
  - 19 letters, 1916-1942, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by A. L. Gump and C. S. James. Relate primarily to restoration and framing Keith paintings. (Box 8)
- Hadley, Edith Jane, 18 91-
  - Letter, June 2, 1955, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Re her research on John Muir.
- Hammond, George Peter, 1896- See Bancroft Library
- Hanner, Wynn (Martin) Pond
  - 11 letters, 1944-1955 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Hardee, Theodore, 1868- See San Francisco. Panama Pacific International Exposition, 1915
- Harmon, Edith E. [William Keith's granddaughter]
  - 2 letters, 1931 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 8)
- Harmon, Edward Newell
  - 11 letters, 1911-1922, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, Nov. 16, 1922, transmits draft of his letter to R. L. Eldridge. Relate mainly to sale of Keith paintings. With these: letter of recommendation (copy) for G. F. Liljestrom, n.d. (Box 8)
- Harmon, Mary Hortense (Keith), 1868-1948. [William Keith's daughter]
  - 2 letters, 1883-1910, to William Keith. (Box 2)
  - 43 letters, 1888-1947, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 8)
  - Letter, June 28, 1883, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
  - 3 letters, 1931-1945, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, April 22, 1883, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
- Harper, Ida A. (Husted), 1851-1931
  - 17 letters, 1896-1924 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, Jan. 16, 1923, written to E. L. Watson. Many letters written while Editor, History of Woman Suffrage. (Box 8)
- Harris, Ambia Corson, 1859-
  - Letter, Oct. 18, 1908, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
- Harris, Harriet Octavia (Corson), 1824-
  - 2 letters, 1881-1888, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
- Harris, Henrietta Clark, d. 1933
  - 3 letters, 1920-1929, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 8)
  - Letter, Dec. 1929, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. Typed extract. (Carton 6)
- Harris, William Brown, 1799-1847
  - Letter, Oct. 17, 1841, to Asa Baldwin Metcalfe. (Box 18)
- Harrison, Francis Burton, 1873-
  - 2 letters, 1906, to William Keith. Re a new painting of Mt. Shasta which Keith made for him to replace one lost in the earthquake and fire. (Box 2)
- Hay, Charles Carter, 1848-
  - 2 letters, 1915-1919, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. (Box 21)
- Hay, Emily Parsons Babcock, d. 1937
  - Letter, 1906, to William Keith. Re the San Francisco earthquake and fire. (Box 2)
  - 140 letters, 1917-1937, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letters, 1917, are copies. (Box 8 9)
  - 8 letters, 1914-1917 and n.d., to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Some letters are copies. (Box 15)
  - Letter, [Nov. 27, 1900], to Elizabeth Harris (McHenry) Lamare. (Box 19)
  - 3 letters, 1935 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 2 letters, 1880 and n.d., to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 2 letters, 1916 and n.d., to Emma (McHenry) Pond. Letter, n.d., is incomplete. (Carton 6)
  - Letter, June 23, 1937, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 7)
  - Letter, May 2, 1937, to Brother Cornelius. Re his article "Keith and Modern Art." (Carton 9)
- Hay, Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe), 1840-1937
  - 8 letters, 1862-1931 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letters, 1916, are copies. (Box 9)
  - 3 letters, 1860-1870 and n.d., to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
  - 3 letters, 1846-1860, to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. (Box 18)
  - Telegram, Nov. 27, 1900, to Elizabeth Harris (McHenry) Lamare. (Box 19)
  - Letter, Feb. 22, 1863, to William Gilbert Hay. (Box 21)
  - 2 letters, 1892, to Emily Parsons Babcock Hay. (Box 21)
- Hay, William Gilbert, 1830-1875
  - Letter, May 4, 1864, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
  - 2 letters, 1864 and n.d., to Elizabeth Harris (McHenry) Lamare. (Box 19)
  - Letter, May 3, 1873, to his son, William Gilbert Hay. (Box 21)
- Hay, William Gilbert, 1867-1900
  - Telegram, June 23, 1876, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. (Box 21)
  - Letter, Mar. 1, 1874, to his father, William Gilbert Hay. (Box 21)
- Hearst, Phoebe Apperson, 1842-1919
  - 4 letters, 1898-1908, to William Keith. Letter, 1898, thanks him for the gift of several Indian baskets. With these: 2 Christmas cards, n.d. (Box 2)
  - 3 letters, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
  - Letter, Oct. 29, 1886, to Elizabeth Harris (McHenry) Lamare. (Box 19)
  - Telegram, Mar. 22, 1915, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. Inviting her to a luncheon at her home in Pleasanton. (Carton 6)
- Henderson, Elizabeth Drown, 1870-1942
  - 24 letters, 1930-1942 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. One letter, n.d., is incomplete. (Box 9)
- Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery
  - 6 letters, 1943-1948, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by L. E. Bliss, Librarian. (Carton 5)
- Herrin, William Franklin, 1854-1927
  - 7 letters, 1906-1910, to William Keith. Letter, Nov. 14, 1910, contains note from Keith to Joseph Worcester. (Box 2)
  - Letter, Apr. 14, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith, re death of William Keith. With this: letter, Apr. 14, 1911, written by his daughter Alice; letter, Mar. 9, 1927, written by his daughter Katherine. (Box 9)
- Higgins, Lawrence D.
  - 3 letters, 1939-1944, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
  - 2 letters, 1947 n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Letter, 1947, concerns possibly nominating Mary (McHenry) Keith Berkeley Citizen of the Year. (Carton 5)
  - Letter (copy), July 13, 1938, to Brother Cornelius. Re the Keith exhibition at the Golden Gate International Exposition. (Carton 9)
- Higgins, Marguerite (Godard) [Mrs. Lawrence D. Higgins]
  - 41 letters, 1925-1946 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Some letters are in French. 2 letters, n.d., are incomplete. With these: 3 letters (copies), 1942? and n.d., from her daughter Marguerite, and copies of articles re her work as war correspondent. (Box 9)
  - Letter, Mar. 24, 1947, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Hill, Roberta Lester Eldridge
  - 24 letters, 1926-1944 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
- Hink, Lester W.
  - 3 letters, 1943-1944, to Brother Cornelius. Letters, 1944, are copies. Re establishing a Keith museum in Berkeley. (Carton 9)
- Hittell, Amy Bowen, d. 1944 [Mrs. Charles Jacob Hittell]
  - 4 letters, 1933-1942 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
- Hittell, Catherine Hermanna
  - Letter, Aug. 9, 1884, to William Keith. (Box 2)
  - 2 letters, 1911-1922, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
  - Letter, Aug. 9, 1884, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
- Hittell, Charles Jacob, 1861-1938
  - Letter, [1911], to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re William Keith's death. (Box 9)
- Hittell, Emily Reynolds (Coey) [Mrs. Franklin Theodore Hittell]
  - 3 letters, 1936-1945, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
  - 2 letters, 1945-1948, to Keith Art Association. (Carton 9)
- Howell, John Gilson, 1874-1956
  - Letter, July 10, 1907, to William Keith. Written for Paul Elder and Company. Re books Keith bought and painting which the Company bought - or perhaps traded for the books. (Box 2)
  - Letter, Feb. 12, 1947, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
- Howison, George Holmes, 1834-1916
  - Postcard, July 13, 1910, to William Keith written for him by Mrs. Howison. With this: Christmas card, n.d. (Box 2)
- Hughes, West
  - 4 letters, 1906, to William Keith. Re arranging a Keith exhibition in Los Angeles. (Box 2)
- Huntington, Collis Potter, 1821-1900
  - Letter, Apr. 16, 1900, to William Keith. Typed copy. Inviting Keith to visit his gallery. (Box 2)
- Hyatt, Elizabeth (Keith) Orange [William Keith's sister]
  - 5 letters, 1913-1919, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
- Hyde, Henry C.
  - Letter, June 10, 1885, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. (Box 21)
- Hyde, Josephine M.
  - 2 postcards, 1910, to William Keith. (Box 2)
- Ina Coolbrith Circle
  - 2 letters, 1931, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by Katharine Carroll, Librarian. Re acquiring a copy of E. K. Pond's book, Songs of Gladness, for their library. (Carton 5)
- Inness, George, 1825-1894
  - Letter, [1893]. Letter of introduction written to Thomas B. Clarke on behalf of William Keith. (Box 3)
- James, George Wharton, 1858-1923
  - Letter, Apr. 22, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re William Keith's death. (Box 9)
- Jones, William Carey, 1854-1923
  - Letter, Dec. 8, 1922, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Seeking financial aid for Professor Albin Putzker. (Box 9)
- Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931
  - 2 letters, 1904-1907, to William Keith. Letter, 1907, written for him by his secretary. Re sending copies of his books to Keith. (Box 3)
  - Letter, Apr. 14, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re William Keith's death. (Box 9)
- Jordan, Jessie L. (Knight) [Mrs. David Starr Jordan]
  - 2 letters, 1924 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
- Junior, Frederic E.
  - Letter, Dec. 6, 1919, to E. N. Harmon. Re wide distribution of fake Keiths. (Box 3)
  - 5 letters, 1911-1922, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Relate primarily to sale of Keith paintings. (Box 9)
- Kahn, Julius, 1861-1924
  - Letter, Dec. 18, 1911, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written while Representative from California. (Carton 6)
- Kansas Equal Suffrage Association
  - Letter, Oct. 28, 1912, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by H. N. Eackler, Secretary. Thanking Mrs. Keith for her financial contribution. (Box 9)
- Keeler, Charles Augustus, 1871-1937
  - 6 letters, 1895-1901, to William Keith. Several letters invite Keith to join him on vacation. With these: two of Keeler's poems (printed copies). (Box 3)
  - 3 letters, 1930-1936, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
- Keeler, Leonarde, 1903-1949
  - Letter, Aug. 15, 1910, to William Keith. Written for him by his father. (Box 3)
- Keeler, Ormeida (Curtis), 1875- [Mrs. Charles Augustus Keeler]
  - 2 letters, 1937, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. One letter written on verso of printed poems by C. A. O. Keeler. (Box 9)
  - Letter, Feb. 6, 1946, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Re the Keith Art Association. (Carton 5)
- Keith, Charles William, 1865-
  - Letter, Jan. 16, 1882, to Elizabeth (Emerson) Keith. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- Keith, Elizabeth (Emerson), 1838-1882 [William Keith's first wife]
  - 2 letters, 1881-1882, to Charles William Keith. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- Keith, Elizabeth (McLatchie) [William Keith's daughter-in-law]
  - Letter, July 16, 1909, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
- Keith, Lucille Marcella (Spitzen) [Mrs. William Charles Keith]
  - 38 letters, 1931-1947 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
  - 3 letters, 1945 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Keith, Mary (McHenry), 1855-1947
  - 9 letters, 1887-1904 and n.d., to William Keith. One letter, n.d., is incomplete. (Box 3)
  - 85 letters, 1862-1893, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
  - 3 letters, 1884-1889 and n.d., to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. (Box 15)
  - 5 letters, 1884-1885, to Elizabeth Harris (McHenry) Lamare. (Box 19)
  - 2 letters, 1884, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. (Box 21)
  - 56 letters, 1899-1937 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Letters, May 10 and Dec. 20, 1899, include notes by Keith. (Carton 5)
  - 9 letters, 1883-1910, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. Several letters include notes by William Keith. (Carton 6)
  - 119 letters, 1922-1947 and n.d., to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 7)
  - 4 letters, 1938-1943, to Charles McHenry Pond. (Carton 8)
  - Letter, Mar. 31, 1936, to Mary Virginia (Pond) Culbertson. (Carton 8)
  - 28 letters, 1934-1947 and n.d., to Brother Cornelius. A few are copies. (Carton 9)
- Keith, William, 1838-1911
  - Letter, June 16, 1884, to E. N. Harmon. (Box 3)
  - 20 letters, 1882-1905 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 9)
  - 7 letters, 1882-1888, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
  - 2 letters, 1883-1884, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. (Box 19)
  - 5 letters, 1904-1911, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, n.d., to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
- Keith, William Charles, 1894- [William Keith's grandson]
  - 7 letters, 1920-1943, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letters, 1931-1933, are copies. (Box 9)
  - Letter, Jan. 13, 1932, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Keith Art Association, Berkeley, Calif. See Cleveland, Theodore Keirstead Whitney, Margaret (Mason)
- Keller, Helen Adams, 1880-
  - Letter, July 29, 1955, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Soliciting funds for the American Foundation for the Blind. (Carton 5)
- Kellogg, Martin, 1828-1903 See Le Conte, Joseph
- Kip, William Ingraham, 1811-1893
  - Letter, Mar. 5, 1881, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Thanking her for sending him a copy of a poem she wrote. (Box 15)
- Kneiss, Emily (Rayburn) [Mrs. Gilbert Harold Kneiss]
  - 4 letters, 1940, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written for the National Woman's Party. (Box 9)
- Knowland, Joseph Russell, 1873-1966 See Committee For Alameda County (Calif.)
- La Follette, Belle (Case) [Mrs. Robert Marion La Follette]
  - Letter, Mar. 22, 1913, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re suffrage work. (Box 10)
- Lamare, Caroline Goddefroy, d. 1906
  - 2 letters, 1906 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written in French. (Box 10)
  - 78 letters, 1869-1881 and n.d., to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. Written in French. (Box 19)
- Lamare, Elizabeth Harris (McHenry), 1850-1907 [Mrs. Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare]
  - 2 letters, 1895, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
  - 7 letters, 1886-1892 and n.d., to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
  - 4 letters, 1880-1884, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. (Box 19)
  - Letter, Feb. 5, 1907, to Emily Parsons Babcock Hay. (Box 21)
  - Letter, n.d., to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
- Lamare, Emmanuel Benjamin, 1848-1916
  - 2 letters, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
  - 18 letters, 1860-1881, to Caroline (Goddefroy) Lamare. (Box 20)
- Lamare, Franois Nicolas, 1821?-1861
  - 11 letters, 1849-1859, to Caroline (Goddefroy) Lamare. (Box 20)
- Lamare, Georges
  - 56 letters, 1862-1906 and n.d., to Caroline (Goddefroy) Lamare. One letter, n.d., is incomplete. (Box 20)
- Latham, Edith See Latham Foundation For the Promotion of Humane Education, Oakland, Calif.
- Latham, Nydine Snow
  - Letter, Jan. 19, 1948, to Keith Art Association. Re contribution to help purchase Keith paintings. (Carton 9)
- Latham Foundation For the Promotion of Humane Education, Oakland, Calif.
  - 15 letters, 1923-1945, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Edith Latham and others. Letter, May 23, 1923, transmits notification of election as a member and a Director. (Box 10)
- Lavarde, Julia (Goddefroy)
  - 26 letters, 1852-1892 and n.d., to Caroline (Goddefroy) Lamare. (Box 20)
- Le Conte, Caroline Eaton, 1864-1945
  - 11 letters, 1927-1936 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Some letters contain recollections of Keith, his studio, etc. (Box 10)
  - Letter, Apr. 29, n.y., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Le Conte, Caroline Elizabeth (Nisbet), ca. 1828-1915 [Mrs. Joseph Le Conte]
  - Letter, n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
- Le Conte, Helen Marion (Gompertz), 1865-1924 [Mrs. Joseph Nisbet Le Conte]
  - 2 letters, 1895-1902, to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 4 letters, 1888-1924, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
  - Letter, ca. 1908, to Marie V. C. Brackenbury. In Miscellaneous Correspondence
- Le Conte, John, 1818-1891
  - Letter, Mar. 19, 1890, to William Keith. Requesting him to act as a pall-bearer at the funeral of Mary A. Graham. (Box 3)
  - Letter, Apr. 2, 1881, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Thanking her for sending him a copy of her book. (Box 15)
- Le Conte, Joseph, 1823-1901
  - Letter (copy), Apr. 29, 1887, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. Letter of recommendation. Includes also note appended by Martin Kellogg. (Box 19)
- Le Conte, Joseph Nisbet, 1870-1950
  - Letter, Mar. 13, 1931, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Liljestrom, Gustav F.
  - 13 letters, 1933-1938, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re his restoration of Keith paintings. (Box 10)
- Linde, Herman
  - 5 letters, 1903-1906 and n.d., to William Keith. Written while Editor, The Standard, Bridgeport, Conn. (Box 3)
- Logan, Josephine Hancock
  - 2 letters, 1939-1940, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, 1940, written while President, Society For Sanity in Art. (Box 10)
- Lummis, Charles Fletcher, 1859-1928
  - 5 letters, 1900-1911, to William Keith. With these: printed list of books written by Lummis. (Box 3)
- McBean, Jennie V.
  - Letter, Apr. 15, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re William Keith's death. (Box 10)
- Macbeth, Robert W.
  - Letter, Mar. 19, 1931, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Macbeth, William
  - 3 letters, 1906-1910, to William Keith. Re exhibiting some paintings in New York. (Box 3)
  - Letter, Sept. 30, 1916, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Thanking her for sending a book about Keith. (Box 10)
- MacDonald, Arthur T.
  - 11 letters, 1944-1947, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Relate mainly to the Keith Art Association. (Carton 5)
  - 2 letters (copies), 1947-1949, to Brother Cornelius. Re controversies about disposition of Keith paintings and royalties due from his biography of Keith. (Carton 9)
- McHenry, Donald Edward, 1895-
  - 3 letters, 1950-1951, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Letters, 1950, written while Park Naturalist, Yosemite National Park. Letter, 1951, written while Director, Yosemite Natural History Association. (Carton 5)
- McHenry, Elizabeth
  - 3 letters, 1841-1844, to John McHenry. (Box 14)
- McHenry, Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe), 1827-1922 [Mrs. John McHenry]
  - 3 letters, 1883-1907, to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 39 letters, 1883-1914 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
  - 57 letters, 1847-1851, to John McHenry. Originals and typed copies. (Box 14)
  - 12 letters, 1847-1850 and n.d., to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. Originals and typed copies. (Box 18)
  - 2 letters, 1850, to Asa Baldwin Metcalfe. (Box 18)
  - 3 letters, 1891-1907, to Elizabeth Harris (McHenry) Lamare. (Box 19)
  - Letter, May 26, 1886, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. (Box 19)
  - 5 letters, 1880-1884, to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 20 letters, 1883-1911, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
- McHenry, Frances (Reynolds), 1862-1942 [Mrs. John McHenry]
  - 2 letters, 1925 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
- McHenry, James
  - 2 letters, 1851-1875, to John McHenry. (Box 14)
- McHenry, Jesse
  - 5 letters, 1851, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
- McHenry, John, 1809-1880
  - 53 letters, 1846-1865, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
  - Letter, Mar. 4, 1851, to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. (Box 18)
  - 8 letters, 1847-1849, to Asa Baldwin Metcalfe. (Box 18)
  - Letter, Jan. 20, 1879, to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
- McHenry, John, 1858-1935
  - 2 letters, 1881-1912, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
- McIntyre, Merodine (Keeler)
  - Letter, Dec. 4, 1936, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re a Keith painting Mrs. Keith gave her.
- McManus, George Stewart
  - 34 letters, 1930-1954, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Marsh, Mary (Harris), 1829-1854
  - Letter, Jan. 28, 1847, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
- Mason, Emma [Amy?] (Harris), d. 1868
  - Letter, Oct. 8, 1847, to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. (Box 18)
- Maxwell, Everett Carroll
  - 15 letters, 1911-1935, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, 1931, is a form letter. Some letters written while Director, Foundation of Western Art, Los Angeles. (Box 10)
- Messenger, Ivan
  - 10 letters, 1950-1951, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Letters, 1950, written while Assistant Director, Historic Art Exhibition, San Diego City and County Centennial Commission. Re lending several Keith paintings for the Exhibition. (Carton 5)
- Metcalfe, Asa Baldwin, 1800-1850
  - 3 letters, 1847-1848, to John McHenry. (Box 14)
  - 4 letters, 1846-1849, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Letter, Dec. 30, 1849, written from California. (Box 16)
  - 8 letters, 1846-1850 and n.d., to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. Letter, July 10, 1849, written from Acapulco. Letters, 1850, written from California. (Box 18)
- Metcalfe, Barbara Allen (Harris), 1802-1891
  - 3 letters, 1862-1889 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
  - Letter, Sept. 7, 1851, to John McHenry. (Box 14)
  - 5 letters, 1889 and n.d., to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - 9 letters, 1846-1850 and n.d., to Asa Baldwin Metcalfe. (Box 18)
- Metcalfe, George Edward, 1829-1900
  - 3 letters, 1856-1883, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - Letter, Dec. 27, 1888, to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. Extract. (Box 18)
  - 2 letters, 1847-1850, to Asa Baldwin Metcalfe. (Box 18)
  - 2 letters, 1885-1888, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. (Box 21)
- Metcalfe, Henry Bascom, 1832-1853
  - Letter, Mar. 10, 1848, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - 3 letters, 1842-1847, to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. (Box 18)
  - Letter, Sept. 8, 1847, to Asa Baldwin Metcalfe. (Box 18)
- Metcalfe, Louise Boarman
  - Letter, Jan. 2, 1887, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
- Metcalfe, Oren, 1810-
  - Letter, Jan. 15, 1848, to John McHenry (Box 14)
  - Letter, Feb. 5, 1847, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - Letter, Mar. 5, 1849, to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. (Box 18)
  - Letter, Nov. 10, 1880, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
  - Letter, June 8, 1849, to unidentified correspondent. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- Metcalfe, Zuleika
  - Letter, Jan. 29, 1850, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry.
- Meyer, F. H.
  - Letter, Oct. 13, 1931, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written while Director, California School of Arts and Crafts, Oakland. (Box 10)
- Michigan Equal Suffrage Association
  - Letter, Sept. 10, 1910, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by A. M. Boutell. (Box 10)
- Miller, Juanita, d. 1970
  - Postcard, Dec. 23, 1953, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Mills, Edgar
  - Letter, Apr. 14, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re William Keith's death. (Box 10)
- Mills, Susan Lincoln (Tolman), 1826-1912
  - Letter, Apr. 15, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re William Keith's death. (Box 10)
- Mississippi Woman Suffrage Association
  - Letter, July 24, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by N. N. Somerville. (Box 10)
- Moffitt, James Kennedy, 1865-1955
  - Letter (copy), June 9, 1944, to Brother Cornelius. Re the possibility of the Keith collection coming to the University of California. (Carton 9)
- Morgan, Mary De Neale, d. 1948
  - Letter, Apr. 15, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re William Keith's death. (Box 10)
- Morley, Grace Louise McCann, 1900- See San Francisco. Museum of Art
- Morrison, May (Treat), 1858-1939 [Mrs. Alexander Francis Morrison]
  - 3 letters, 1936, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re visiting St. Mary's College to see the Keith paintings. (Box 10)
- Morwood, Mary Elizabeth (Bell), d. 1939
  - Postcard, Jan. 14, n.y., to William Keith. Verso is photograph of Col. and Mrs. Morwood and their daughter Josephine Elizabeth. (Box 3)
  - 13 letters, 1911-1939 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
  - 3 letters, 1930-1932, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Muir, John, 1838-1914
  - 11 letters, 1872-1911, to William Keith. Letter, 1911, transmits clippings re John Burroughs and Muir. (Box 3)
  - 2 letters (copies), [1889?]-1913. Letter, [1889?], is incomplete and probably written to his wife. Letter, 1913, written to Mrs. McChesney. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- National American Woman Suffrage Association See also: Avery, Rachel G. (Foster) Catt, Carrie Chapman Shaw, Anna Howard Upton, Harriet Taylor
  - 2 letters, 1901-1919, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by C. L. Dean and K. M. Gordon. (Box 10)
- National Council of Women Voters